Mark Perez

Fargo, North Dakota | 760-224-0331 | info@markperez.dev | www.markperez.dev

Summary of Qualifications

SEO Specialist certified in Google Search Ads, Analytics, and Display Ads. Additional experience in Javascript and WordPress. Out-of-the-box creative problem solver, capable of meeting deadlines under pressure. Detail-oriented with exceptional communication skills. Deeply invested in learning and surpassing new marketing-related techniques.

Skills & Certifications

- SEO (Search Engine Optimization)
- Digital Marketing
- WordPress
- Brand Awareness
- Social Media Platforms
- ➤ Google Ads Display Certification
- ➤ Google Analytics Individual Qualification

- Google Ads & Google Analytics 4
- Project Management
- HTML, Javascript, CSS
- Website Creation
- Ad Research & Testing
- ➤ Google Ads Search Certification

Experience

Experience Care | United States (Remote) | April 2021 - Present

SEO Strategist

- Develop keyword research and pillars for SEO strategy for long term care SaaS platform.
- Designed, ran, and promoted biweekly email newsletter focused and targeted towards healthcare residents.
- Perform weekly and monthly analysis to ensure that all content campaigns are effective and introduce modifications when necessary.
- Garnered new online ratings for company through email streams and warm outreach.
- Mentor incoming interns to perform concurrent marketing projects.

SkinSolutions.MD | San Diego, CA | December 2019 - April 2021

Digital Advertising Coordinator

- Provide SEO analysis and recommendations in coordination with elements and structure of websites and blog pages.
- Assisted with ongoing Google Ads optimizations including ad copy testing, bid adjustments, budget pacing, negative keyword and long tail keyword expansion, ad customizers, and scripts.
- Monitor growth of marketing campaigns by using tools such as Ahrefs, SEMrush, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, and Surfer SEO.
- Within the first few months, substantial growth was noticed and featured on page 1 search results along with featured snippets.
- Introduced a new paid advertising source to the company through Google Dynamic Geo Location Insertion that would show the location of the end user in the online ad.

Esidarap Inc. | Seattle, WA | September 2019 - December 2019

SEO Apprentice

- Provided technical SEO recommendations to ensure website foundation for both users and search engines (Site Speed, CDN, Cache optimization).
- On-page optimization (pulled keywords from Google Search Console, created enticing meta data, conducted thorough content audits).
- Suggest and implement new on-page tactics to help core pages rank and convert.
- Added additional code to apply style and improve user interface design.

Education

Palomar College | San Marcos, CA

Major: Computer Science, August 2018 - May 2019